REBECCA SCHRADER

34E Fernleigh Drive, Castleknock, Dublin 15

Mobile: (353) 0838 72 2970 / Email: RMSchrader1994@gmail.com Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/Rebecca-schrader-076731109

PROFILE

Qualified Multimedia Developer with a Bachelor's degree in Communications from Salisbury University, and Level 5 Diploma in Software Development from the Code Institute, Dublin. Two years relevant work experience in Education and Public Relations settings, creating and producing original content from storyboard through post-production, while demonstrating a keen ability to creatively interpret a brief and to contribute insightfully to business discussions. Seeking to apply and grow my skills in a junior developer position within a dynamic setting where my perspective is valued and my limits are tested.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Diploma in Software Development (EQF Level 5) Code Institute, Dublin.

Jan - Apr 2018

Introductory Certificate in CSS & XHTML College of Southern Maryland, La Plata, Maryland U.S.A.

Aug - Oct 2017

B.A. Honours, Communication Arts (Media Production) Salisbury University, Maryland U.S.A.

Aug 2013 - Jun 2017

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Marketing & Programme Intern, WorkandTravel.ie

Oct 2019 - Present

Updated and maintained multiple social media outlooks (Facebook, Instagram, & Instagram).
 While also increasing companies presence on college campuses through information stands and talks.

Accommodation Assistant, The Key Collection

Mar 2019 - Oct 2019

• Efficiently provided clean, safe, and hospitable accommodations to clients. Reduced company costs by identifying unnecessary duplication in complementary food and beverages supplied to hotel and apartment guests.

In-Store Demonstrator, Field Management Ireland

Oct 2018 - Feb 2019

Introduced and sold products to customers through in-store demonstrations. Developed
effective presentation and sales skills, resulting in sale of entire inventory over Black Friday
sales period.

Communications Intern, Irish Academy of Public Relations

Jan - Jun 2017

 Filmed Academy Director Ellen Gunning's presentations at national-level conference and corporate events, and classroom activity in courses held at the Academy. Successfully produced over 150 promotional and educational videos from my footage (often under intense time pressure), and distributed them to an international online audience. Updated, maintained, and significantly expanded the Academy's social media footprint, especially on YouTube.

Teacher's Aide, Salisbury University

Sept – Dec 2016

 Assisted in teaching 2D Animation undergraduate class, and led lessons in absence of more senior Faculty. Commended by Professor for the technical quality of material produced by my students, all of whom successfully completed the course.

Distance Learning Facilitator, Salisbury University

Sept 2015 - Dec 2016

 Worked unsupervised to set up, monitor, and troubleshoot digital broadcasts between Salisbury University main campus and satellite sites. Achieved 100 percent success rate in providing unbroken communications to students on remote campuses state-wide.

TECHNICAL & IT SKILLS

- **Software Development:** HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ruby/Python, GitHub, MySQL, Django
- Administrative & Creative: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook); Social Media, including YouTube, Twitter, LinkedIn
- Audio-Visual: Avid, Sony Vegas, Adobe Creative Cloud (After Effects, Dreamweaver, Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop, Premiere)
- Portfolio: https://rmschrader1994.github.io/Portfolio/

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS

- 1. Rose from Audio Technician to Executive Producer at SU-TV public access television channel. (Sep 2013 Dec 2016)
- 2. Co-Leader of Brownie Troop #110, as part of a non-profit mentoring programme for underprivileged children in Wicomico County, Maryland. (Sep 2015 May 2016)

INTERESTS

- 1. International travel. I've travelled independently to Canada, Germany, France, Switzerland and Scotland, and in company to Australia, New Zealand, England and Wales. I enjoy the feeling of confidence and independence I get when I travel on my own and navigate successfully through situations I've never been in before. It makes me realize I can take on things beyond my usual comfort zone, and make a success of them.
- 2. I perform freelance Web design, and film and produce promotional videos, for small business customers. This allows me to practice my creative design and development skills, and to keep my software skills current during those periods when I am employed outside my field.

U.S. / U.K. dual national References available on request